<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>silverbirder</title>
    <link>https://silverbirder.github.io/en-US/blog/</link>
    <description>silverbirder's blog</description>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <item>
      <title>Impressions After 7 Months of a 4-Day Workweek</title>
      <link>https://silverbirder.github.io/en-US/blog/contents/reflections-after-7-months-4-day-workweek/</link>
      <description>Starting in February 2024, I began working as a freelance frontend engineer in the web industry, working four days a week. My working days are Monday, Tuesday, Thursday, and Friday. In this post, I reflect on these seven months and share my thoughts.</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Sep 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <category>Working</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>GPT-Driven Development： Efficient App Development with GPTs</title>
      <link>https://silverbirder.github.io/en-US/blog/contents/gpt-driven-development/</link>
      <description>In GPT-driven development, the ability to assess the accuracy of AI-generated outputs is essential. Rather than relying entirely on GPT, active involvement from developers is required.</description>
      <pubDate>Sun, 15 Sep 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <category>GPT</category>
      <category>ChatGPT</category>
      <category>V0</category>
      <category>LogoAI</category>
      <category>DiagramGPT</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>My First Mobile App Development Attempt and Why I Gave Up</title>
      <link>https://silverbirder.github.io/en-US/blog/contents/first-mobile-app-failure/</link>
      <description>After working on a mobile app for about three months, I ultimately decided to abandon the project. In short, the restrictions on iOS background execution made it impossible to create what I envisioned. In this article, I’ll share the development process and explain why I gave up. Whew, it was exhausting!</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <category>React Native</category>
      <category>Learn</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Switched from Long-Used iPhone to Google Pixel</title>
      <link>https://silverbirder.github.io/en-US/blog/contents/switching-from-iphone-to-google-pixel-8a/</link>
      <description>Introduction I have switched from a long-used iPhone to Google Pixel. In this article, I will discuss the reasons and impressions.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Created an App to Consistently Record and Visualize Data in a Free Format</title>
      <link>https://silverbirder.github.io/en-US/blog/contents/introducing-kotsu-kotsu-app/</link>
      <description>I created "Kotsu-Kotsu", a web app that allows you to consistently record and visualize anything!</description>
      <pubDate>Sat, 25 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <category>Artifact</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Frontend Development Techniques in the Age of Generative AI</title>
      <link>https://silverbirder.github.io/en-US/blog/contents/frontend-development-in-the-age-of-generative-ai/</link>
      <description>ChatGPT was released in November 2022, and about a year and a half has passed. I have been continuously using ChatGPT since it became a hot topic. Using ChatGPT has proven to be beneficial for frontend development of web applications. Therefore, in this article, I have summarized three patterns for efficiently advancing frontend development by utilizing ChatGPT. I hope that these patterns will be useful to readers in their development projects. Below are the Figma, source code, and deployment URLs introduced in this article.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <category>AI</category>
      <category>Figma</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Trying Out container-structure-test on a Docker Image</title>
      <link>https://silverbirder.github.io/en-US/blog/contents/try-container-structure-test/</link>
      <description>Discovered `container-structure-test` for verifying if the structure and settings within a Docker image are as expected. Check out the container-structure-test GitHub repository. Decided to give it a try.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 29 Mar 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <category>Test</category>
      <category>Docker</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Integration Testing for Next.js and DB using Testcontainers</title>
      <link>https://silverbirder.github.io/en-US/blog/contents/testcontainers-nextjs-db-integration/</link>
      <description>I learned about Testcontainers. Testcontainers is a tool that allows you to build a test environment using containers and easily perform integration testing.Using this convenient tool, I conducted integration testing combining Next.js and a database (DB).It seems promising for implementing disposable end-to-end (E2E) tests, and I found it very useful. I'll briefly introduce what I tried.</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Mar 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <category>Test</category>
      <category>Testcontainers</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Trying Million Lint</title>
      <link>https://silverbirder.github.io/en-US/blog/contents/try-million-lint/</link>
      <description>I learned about Million.dev and decided to give it a try. About Million.js This library seems to make profiling easier than using React DevTools' Profiler. Profiling performance is usually a cumbersome and time-consuming task. If this can make it easier, I was quite excited about the prospects.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 21 Mar 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <category>Test</category>
      <category>Lint</category>
      <category>Performance</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Trying the Playwright Component Test</title>
      <link>https://silverbirder.github.io/en-US/blog/contents/try-playwright-component-testing/</link>
      <description>I learned about "Playwright Component Test" (hereafter referred to as "playwright-ct"), which allows you to run component tests in the browser directly on Playwright, and tried it out. In this article, we share our experience. The actual repository used is as follows</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Mar 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <category>Test</category>
      <category>Playwright</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>I want to do Document Testing with Typescript</title>
      <link>https://silverbirder.github.io/en-US/blog/contents/try-document-testing/</link>
      <description>If you are a TypeScript developer, you may have written documentation in your code. It seems that you can write documentation tests for your documentation. This article introduces some tools to perform documentation tests in TypeScript.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 14 Mar 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <category>Test</category>
      <category>Document</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Installed Disqus!</title>
      <link>https://silverbirder.github.io/en-US/blog/contents/install-disqus-on-my-site/</link>
      <description>Until now, I had installed Giscus as a comment service on my blog site. Today, I switched to the same comment service, Disqus.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 Mar 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>I Tried Morning Mindfulness Meditation for a Month</title>
      <link>https://silverbirder.github.io/en-US/blog/contents/mindfulness-meditation-beginner/</link>
      <description>So far, I have been honing my hard and soft skills. Recently, I started thinking about improving my self-management skills through books. Therefore, I continued mindfulness meditation every morning for about a month, and I will write about the experience and the results obtained here.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Mar 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <category>Tips</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How to Mock tRPC Communication on Storybook with MSW</title>
      <link>https://silverbirder.github.io/en-US/blog/contents/trpc-msw-mocking/</link>
      <description>tRPC is a framework that allows you to easily build type-safe APIs. During development, if you want to proceed with front-end development on Storybook without waiting for the backend implementation, you can mock the API using Mock Service Worker (MSW). This article explains how to mock tRPC communication with MSW using maloguertin/msw-trpc. As a practical example, the sample code is shared on the GitHub repository silverbirder/trpc-msw-storybook-nextjs.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Mar 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <category>Test</category>
      <category>Tips</category>
      <category>MSW</category>
      <category>tRPC</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Paper drivers enjoy driving.</title>
      <link>https://silverbirder.github.io/en-US/blog/contents/from-paper-driver-to-road-adventures/</link>
      <description>I was a paper driver and it has been 4 months since I bought my new car. At first I was full of anxiety, but now I look forward to my week of driving. Here is the process that led to this change.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 22 Feb 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <category>Car</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Getting Familiar with Figma</title>
      <link>https://silverbirder.github.io/en-US/blog/contents/becoming-friends-with-figma/</link>
      <description>So far, I have been implementing the web frontend while referring to the wonderful Figma artifacts created by designers. As I experienced this over and over, I wanted to become proficient in using Figma.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 Feb 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <category>Figma</category>
      <category>CSS</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Convenience of Google Map Timeline</title>
      <link>https://silverbirder.github.io/en-US/blog/contents/tips-google-maps-timeline/</link>
      <description>When I went to a shopping mall by car, the parking fee was free for up to one hour from entry, but I had a vague memory of "When did I enter?". At such times, when I looked at the timeline of Google Map, I knew exactly what time and minute I arrived, and I really felt it was convenient.</description>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Feb 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <category>Tips</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Developing "Bochi-Bochi", an App to Easily Find Cheap Ingredients</title>
      <link>https://silverbirder.github.io/en-US/blog/contents/bochi-bochi-app-development/</link>
      <description>Is the cabbage at this supermarket a bit expensive? Is there anywhere else cheaper? From such small daily questions, we have developed a web app "Bochi-Bochi" that allows you to easily compare the prices of ingredients at different supermarkets.</description>
      <pubDate>Sat, 10 Feb 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <category>Artifact</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Looking back at 2023. Home, Car, and Me</title>
      <link>https://silverbirder.github.io/en-US/blog/contents/2023_furikaeri/</link>
      <description>It suddenly got cold, didn't it? Just a week ago, I could get by in short sleeves, but now heating is essential. We're already halfway through November, and there's not much left of this year. So, I'd like to look back at 2023.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Nov 2023 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <category>Looking Back</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>E2E Testing with Cucumber and Screenplay Design</title>
      <link>https://silverbirder.github.io/en-US/blog/contents/e2e-testing-with-cucumber-and-screenplay-design/</link>
      <description>Automated testing is essential in web application development. Especially, the importance of E2E testing before release is high. This time, I will introduce my experience of incorporating the famous Cucumber and Screenplay design in BDD.</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 13 Nov 2023 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <category>Cucumber</category>
      <category>Screenplay</category>
      <category>Test</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>What I Learned from Refreshing My Blog Page with Qwik</title>
      <link>https://silverbirder.github.io/en-US/blog/contents/replace_my_portfolio_by_qwik_v3/</link>
      <description>Hello, I'm @silverbirder. Recently, I refreshed my blog page with the Qwik framework. The link below is the refreshed page.</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 Oct 2023 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <category>Portfolio</category>
      <category>Artifact</category>
      <category>Qwik</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Introducing AI Ghostwriter - A Tool to Improve Writing Efficiency</title>
      <link>https://silverbirder.github.io/en-US/blog/contents/writing_efficiency_tool_introducing_ai_ghostwriter/</link>
      <description>Recently, I, silverbirder, have been hooked on Beard Papa's baked cheesecake puff. As someone who struggles with writing, I developed a Chrome extension called "AI Ghostwriter" that allows AI to write on my behalf. In this article, I will introduce this handy tool.</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Jul 2023 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <category>Chrome Extension</category>
      <category>ChatGPT</category>
      <category>AI</category>
      <category>Artifact</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Boosting TOEIC Score by 285 Points in 6 Months</title>
      <link>https://silverbirder.github.io/en-US/blog/contents/increased_TOEIC_score_by_285_points_in_6_months/</link>
      <description>I started studying English and managed to boost my TOEIC score by 285 points in just 6 months. I'm writing this article to share my experience and record my learning journey.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Jul 2023 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <category>TOEIC</category>
      <category>English</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Getting Started with Feature Flags in Unleash</title>
      <link>https://silverbirder.github.io/en-US/blog/contents/unleash_feature_flag/</link>
      <description>Are you familiar with Feature Flags? They are a powerful tool that makes it easy to control the release of new features and conduct A/B testing. However, managing feature flags is not easy without the right management tool. In this article, we will discuss **Unleash**, a tool that streamlines the management of feature flags.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 29 Jun 2023 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <category>Unleash</category>
      <category>DevOps</category>
      <category>Survey</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Comprehensive Testing Pattern Guide for Web Frontend</title>
      <link>https://silverbirder.github.io/en-US/blog/contents/web_frontend_test_pattern_guide/</link>
      <description>Hello, I am silverbirder who loves testing. Are you conducting tests on your Web frontend? I believe unit tests and visual regression tests are widely known. However, do you have test codes for performance tests? Also, do you have chaos engineering tests and accessibility tests?</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 Apr 2023 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <category>Frontend</category>
      <category>Test</category>
      <category>React</category>
      <category>Jest</category>
      <category>Storybook</category>
      <category>Cucumber</category>
      <category>Playwright</category>
      <category>Performance</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Stuck on the path in zod's refine</title>
      <link>https://silverbirder.github.io/en-US/blog/contents/zod_refine_path/</link>
      <description>I was using zod's refine, but I couldn't understand how to use the path at all, and I got stuck for about an hour, so I'll leave it as a memo.</description>
      <pubDate>Sat, 07 Jan 2023 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <category>zod</category>
      <category>Scrap</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Automating Synchronization with GitHub Actions and Pull Requests</title>
      <link>https://silverbirder.github.io/en-US/blog/contents/automated_synchronisation_using_github_actions_and_pull_requests/</link>
      <description>Happy New Year. I am silverbirder, who drew the best fortune for the first time in my life at a shrine. I feel that the communication to synchronize things like Figma's design tokens, API schema files, and i18n message files to the frontend in my daily work is unproductive. Therefore, I will introduce a mechanism to reduce synchronization communication using GitHub Actions and Pull Requests.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Jan 2023 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <category>GitHub Actions</category>
      <category>DevOps</category>
      <category>GitHub</category>
      <category>Survey</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Looking back to 2022. Career change and fertility</title>
      <link>https://silverbirder.github.io/en-US/blog/contents/2022_furikaeri/</link>
      <description>We are approaching the end of the year 2022. I am going to look back on this year.This will be written for myself, so I will structure my writing and do it inappropriately.</description>
      <pubDate>Sat, 03 Dec 2022 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <category>Looking Back</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>I read 'Micro Frontends'</title>
      <link>https://silverbirder.github.io/en-US/blog/contents/review_of_micro-frontends_book/</link>
      <description>I read Micro Frontends written by Luca Mezzalira from DAZN. I thought I'd leave a simple book review.</description>
      <pubDate>Sun, 13 Nov 2022 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <category>Micro Frontends</category>
      <category>Review</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Committing to Git from iPhone using Obsidian</title>
      <link>https://silverbirder.github.io/en-US/blog/contents/obsidian-git-muti-device/</link>
      <description>I like the concept of WikiWikiWeb, and I like Obsidian and Scrapbox, which include this concept. Obsidian has a Git integration plugin called obsidian-git. With this, you can now Git Commit not only from your desktop but also from your mobile.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Oct 2022 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <category>Obsidian</category>
      <category>Git</category>
      <category>iPhone</category>
      <category>Scrap</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The GraphQL Guild Ecosystem is Convenient, Isn't It?</title>
      <link>https://silverbirder.github.io/en-US/blog/contents/graphql_guild_ecosystem_is_useful/</link>
      <description>Do you know about the GraphQL Guild? In the GraphQL community, Code Generator is well-known, but...</description>
      <pubDate>Sat, 15 Oct 2022 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <category>GraphQL</category>
      <category>Survey</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Crawlee is Handy for Quick Crawling</title>
      <link>https://silverbirder.github.io/en-US/blog/contents/crawlee-was-useful-for-crawling/</link>
      <description>There are times when you want to scrape data. I found the OSS Crawlee to be useful, so I'm sharing it.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Sep 2022 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <category>Crawlee</category>
      <category>Crawler</category>
      <category>Survey</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Self-hosting a Cache Server with turborepo-remote-cache</title>
      <link>https://silverbirder.github.io/en-US/blog/contents/self-hosted_cache_server_with_turborepo-remote-cache/</link>
      <description>Vercel's build system, turborepo, is a super-fast monorepo tool. One of the features that make it super-fast is the remote cache. This feature uses Vercel's cache server, but there is also a way to self-host the cache server. In this article, I will introduce that.</description>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Sep 2022 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <category>Turborepo</category>
      <category>Monorepo</category>
      <category>Vercel</category>
      <category>Survey</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Tried Running ERNIE-ViLG on Google Colaboratory</title>
      <link>https://silverbirder.github.io/en-US/blog/contents/ernie_vilg_demo/</link>
      <description>I came across an article stating that ERNIE-ViLG is strong with "2D characters". I tried to use it on the next page, but the response was not very good. So, I referred to the following article and started running ERNIE-ViLG on Google Colaboratory.</description>
      <pubDate>Sat, 03 Sep 2022 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <category>ERNIE-ViLG</category>
      <category>AI</category>
      <category>Google Colaboratory</category>
      <category>Scrap</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Development of Stable Diffusion API</title>
      <link>https://silverbirder.github.io/en-US/blog/contents/using_stability_ai_API/</link>
      <description>Stable Diffusion is an open-source AI that generates images when you give it text. If you want to run it on your own, you will need a GPU.</description>
      <pubDate>Sat, 03 Sep 2022 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <category>Stable Diffusion</category>
      <category>API</category>
      <category>AI</category>
      <category>Artifact</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Useful Prompt Phrase Collection for Midjourney and StableDiffusion</title>
      <link>https://silverbirder.github.io/en-US/blog/contents/prompt_phrases_useful_in_Midjourney_StableDiffusion/</link>
      <description>When using Midjourney or StableDiffusion, you may not know what phrases to use. Therefore, I thought it would be helpful to create a collection of phrases for use with Prompt.</description>
      <pubDate>Sun, 28 Aug 2022 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <category>Midjourney</category>
      <category>Stable Diffusion</category>
      <category>AI</category>
      <category>Scrap</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Trying to Integrate Dagger for CI/CD with GithubActions and CircleCI</title>
      <link>https://silverbirder.github.io/en-US/blog/contents/try_dagger/</link>
      <description>I tried out Dagger, a tool for CI/CD that I've been curious about for a while, which is not vendor-locked. In this article, I will share what I tried.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 Aug 2022 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <category>Dagger</category>
      <category>CI</category>
      <category>CD</category>
      <category>GitHub Actions</category>
      <category>CircleCI</category>
      <category>DevOps</category>
      <category>Scrap</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Trying out connect-web</title>
      <link>https://silverbirder.github.io/en-US/blog/contents/try_connect_web/</link>
      <description>An article about connect-web was trending on Hatena Bookmark. I was curious, so I tried it out. The sample code is placed in the following repository.</description>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 Aug 2022 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <category>gRPC</category>
      <category>React</category>
      <category>Scrap</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Trying Data Transformation with urql</title>
      <link>https://silverbirder.github.io/en-US/blog/contents/urql_transform_exchange/</link>
      <description>When using a GraphQL client, you may want to transform the data after fetching it. I found that exchanges in the GraphQL client urql can be used for data transformation, so I will share that.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Aug 2022 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <category>GraphQL</category>
      <category>urql</category>
      <category>React</category>
      <category>Survey</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>History of GraphQL</title>
      <link>https://silverbirder.github.io/en-US/blog/contents/a_brief_history_of_graphql/</link>
      <description>I started using GraphQL in my work. As usual, I was curious about the history of GraphQL, so I looked into it.</description>
      <pubDate>Sat, 30 Jul 2022 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <category>GraphQL</category>
      <category>History</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Debugging with JavaScript's debugger (Browser/Node.js/Jest)</title>
      <link>https://silverbirder.github.io/en-US/blog/contents/Lets_debug_with_JavaScript_debugger/</link>
      <description>Let's debug using the standard JavaScript feature `debugger`. Since it's a standard feature, it can be used in libraries like React.</description>
      <pubDate>Sat, 09 Jul 2022 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <category>JavaScript</category>
      <category>Debugger</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Understanding Browser Layout and Paint</title>
      <link>https://silverbirder.github.io/en-US/blog/contents/know_your_browser_layout_and_paint/</link>
      <description>I was curious about layout and paint in the browser's rendering engine, so I researched it. This article summarizes what I found. The rendering engine I will focus on is Chrome's Blink.</description>
      <pubDate>Sun, 03 Jul 2022 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <category>Browser</category>
      <category>Layout</category>
      <category>Paint</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>This Body is Made of Pondering</title>
      <link>https://silverbirder.github.io/en-US/blog/contents/this_body_is_made_of_ponderings/</link>
      <description>Mister Donut, a shop that produces the ultimate donuts. I will talk about my encounter, parting, and reunion with Mister Donut.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 30 Jun 2022 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <category>Mister Donut</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Part-time Jobs I Experienced as a Student</title>
      <link>https://silverbirder.github.io/en-US/blog/contents/part_time_jobs_I_had_as_a_student/</link>
      <description>I did various part-time jobs when I was a student. I thought I would record them so I wouldn't forget.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 Jun 2022 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <category>Student</category>
      <category>Part Time</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Things I learned when I started using React at work</title>
      <link>https://silverbirder.github.io/en-US/blog/contents/what_I_learned_when_I_started_using_React_in_my_work/</link>
      <description>Until now, I had only used React in my private life. Recently, I've had more opportunities to use React at work, so I thought I'd document what I've learned.</description>
      <pubDate>Sat, 25 Jun 2022 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <category>React</category>
      <category>Learn</category>
      <category>History</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Defining Fragments Composed in Micro Frontends as Web Components and Sharing them with Module Federation</title>
      <link>https://silverbirder.github.io/en-US/blog/contents/fragments_to_be_composed_in_Micro_Frontends_are_defined_in_Web_Components_and_shared_in_Module_Federation/</link>
      <description>A brief introduction on how to define fragments composed in Micro Frontends (hereafter, MFE) as Web Components and share them with Module Federation.</description>
      <pubDate>Sat, 28 May 2022 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <category>Web Components</category>
      <category>Module Federation</category>
      <category>Micro Frontends</category>
      <category>Artifact</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How to display Twitter embedded content in an iframe after rendering</title>
      <link>https://silverbirder.github.io/en-US/blog/contents/how_to_display_embedded_twitter_content_after_rendering_on_iframe/</link>
      <description>The conclusion is to find the `twttr` object from `iframe.contentWindow` and write the display process as the second argument of `event.bind("rendered", () =&gt; {})`. The background is that you want to display embedded content from a URL like `https://twitter.com/openwc/status/1427617679427440643` on a blog site. The html in the response of `https://publish.twitter.com/oembed?url=${URL}` becomes the embedded content. By setting this to the srcdoc of the iframe, you can display the embedded content.</description>
      <pubDate>Sun, 22 May 2022 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <category>Twitter</category>
      <category>Survey</category>
      <category>iframe</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Created OEmbed and OGP WebComponents for use on my blog site</title>
      <link>https://silverbirder.github.io/en-US/blog/contents/publish_my_web_components/</link>
      <description>I have created the following two Web Components.</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 11 Apr 2022 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <category>Web Components</category>
      <category>OEmbed</category>
      <category>OGP</category>
      <category>Artifact</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Developing an oEmbed component with WebComponents and what I learned</title>
      <link>https://silverbirder.github.io/en-US/blog/contents/what_i_learned_from_developing_o_embed_web_components/</link>
      <description>I developed and released an oEmbed component with WebComponents. I would like to list what I learned during the development.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 25 Mar 2022 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <category>Web Components</category>
      <category>OEmbed</category>
      <category>Learn</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Thoughts on Using Ruby on Rails in Business</title>
      <link>https://silverbirder.github.io/en-US/blog/contents/started_using_ruby_on_rails_at_work./</link>
      <description>Since January 2022, I started using Ruby on Rails (hereinafter, Rails) at my new workplace. I have experience with PHP's CakePHP, Node.js's Express, and Python's Flask, but I had a hard time getting used to Rails. I will try to articulate this loosely. By the way, this was also my first time using Ruby.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 Mar 2022 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <category>Ruby on Rails</category>
      <category>Learn</category>
      <category>Scrap</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Knowing the History Before Learning React</title>
      <link>https://silverbirder.github.io/en-US/blog/contents/know_the_history_before_learning_React/</link>
      <description>What is this? I will briefly introduce the history of why React was born. (Just a little research) Background Recently, I started learning React. In the process, I wondered why I should learn React and what features it has.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 11 Mar 2022 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <category>React</category>
      <category>Learn</category>
      <category>History</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Goodness of Web Components</title>
      <link>https://silverbirder.github.io/en-US/blog/contents/the_goodness_of_web_components./</link>
      <description>I want to recommend Web Components to people. I would like to summarize the advantages and disadvantages simply. I will quote from Web Components is what https://www.webcomponents.org/specs.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Mar 2022 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <category>Web Components</category>
      <category>Goodness</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Writing about what I learned from being infected with the Omicron variant</title>
      <link>https://silverbirder.github.io/en-US/blog/contents/covid-19-omicron-knowledge/</link>
      <description>On January 24, 2022, I was infected with the Omicron variant. There was a lot I didn't know, so I thought I'd write about what I learned. Please note that this is based on my personal experience, and I don't know if it's generally applicable.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 Jan 2022 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <category>COVID-19</category>
      <category>Omicron</category>
      <category>Learn</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Things I Learned from Developing Chrome Extensions (Manifest V3)</title>
      <link>https://silverbirder.github.io/en-US/blog/contents/chrome_extension_development_feedback/</link>
      <description>Do you know about Chrome extensions? Chrome extensions are features for customizing the Chrome browser. If you want to know more about Chrome extensions, please check out What are extensions? - Chrome Developers.</description>
      <pubDate>Sun, 16 Jan 2022 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <category>Chrome Extension</category>
      <category>Manifest V3</category>
      <category>Artifact</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>If you're writing in Markdown, Rocket, an SSG that uses WebComponents, is recommended!</title>
      <link>https://silverbirder.github.io/en-US/blog/contents/intro_rocket/</link>
      <description>Are you writing blogs or documents in Markdown? Have you ever felt frustrated that you can't reach the itchy parts with just Markdown when you want to focus on writing? For such people, I recommend Rocket, a static site generator (hereinafter referred to as SSG) that seamlessly integrates Markdown and WebComponents.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 Dec 2021 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <category>Markdown</category>
      <category>Rocket</category>
      <category>Portfolio</category>
      <category>SSG</category>
      <category>Web Components</category>
      <category>Artifact</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Refreshing Silverbirder's Portfolio Page (v2)</title>
      <link>https://silverbirder.github.io/en-US/blog/contents/replace_my_portfolio_v2/</link>
      <description>I have refreshed my portfolio page. In this article, I would like to introduce the motivation for the refresh, the content of the refresh, and the future.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Dec 2021 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <category>Portfolio</category>
      <category>Artifact</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Looking back to 20211</title>
      <link>https://silverbirder.github.io/en-US/blog/contents/2021_furikaeri/</link>
      <description>The year 2021 is now just around the corner. I will leave my reflections on this year on my blog.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 Dec 2021 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <category>Looking Back</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>I Made an API That Only Returns Google Account Images</title>
      <link>https://silverbirder.github.io/en-US/blog/contents/intro_google_account_photo_api/</link>
      <description>How do you manage your profile picture? For example, do you update your Zenn profile picture? I often neglect to update my profile picture because it's a hassle. (It would be nice if we could use a SaaS like Gravatar...)</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Dec 2021 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <category>Google</category>
      <category>API</category>
      <category>Artifact</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Mockable unit testing methodology completed only with BigQuery</title>
      <link>https://silverbirder.github.io/en-US/blog/contents/a_mockable_unit_testing_method_that_can_be_completed_only_with_big_query/</link>
      <description>BigQuery, do you use it? I am building data using BigQuery in my work. For quality assurance, I want to test against BigQuery SQL.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 Nov 2021 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <category>HTML</category>
      <category>BigQuery</category>
      <category>Mock</category>
      <category>Test</category>
      <category>Survey</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Impressions after having casual interviews with 10 companies</title>
      <link>https://silverbirder.github.io/en-US/blog/contents/my_feedback_after_taking_casual_interviews_with_10_companies_in_2_months/</link>
      <description>The story of a 47-year-old who is retiring in 100 days is a hot topic on Twitter. While those posts were ongoing, I was job hunting. I would like to briefly summarize the content of that activity and my impressions.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Nov 2021 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <category>Casual Interview</category>
      <category>Review</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Introduction to LLVM - Compiling JavaScript to LLVM (Rust:inkwell) JIT</title>
      <link>https://silverbirder.github.io/en-US/blog/contents/intro_to_LLVM-JIT_compilation_of_javascript_with_LLVM_Rust_inkwell/</link>
      <description>I, who had no knowledge of LLVM, a compiler infrastructure, have managed to parse JavaScript source code and compile it with LLVM. There are many articles about LLVM, but I felt there were few for beginners, so in this article, I will try to write an article that can introduce LLVM as simply as possible. The source code is placed here.</description>
      <pubDate>Sat, 04 Sep 2021 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <category>LLVM</category>
      <category>Javascript</category>
      <category>Rust</category>
      <category>Inkwell</category>
      <category>JIT</category>
      <category>Survey</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Building a TikTok Scraping Infrastructure on GCP and the Challenges Faced</title>
      <link>https://silverbirder.github.io/en-US/blog/contents/learn_point_from_building_tiktok_scrape_platform_on_gcp/</link>
      <description>We have built a batch to scrape TikTok on GCP. We will share the system design story of GCP construction and the challenges we faced during the construction.</description>
      <pubDate>Sat, 28 Aug 2021 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <category>TikTok</category>
      <category>GCP</category>
      <category>Learn</category>
      <category>Artifact</category>
      <category>Scraping</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Learning How Browsers Work</title>
      <link>https://silverbirder.github.io/en-US/blog/contents/learning_browser_engine/</link>
      <description>As a web front-end engineer, it's only natural to be interested in how browsers work. In this article, I will document the process of learning about the workings of a browser.</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 May 2021 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <category>Browser</category>
      <category>Learn</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>It's become harder to "ask casually" since remote work started</title>
      <link>https://silverbirder.github.io/en-US/blog/contents/good_and_bad_in_offline_and_online/</link>
      <description>With the increasing prevalence of remote work, many engineers are getting used to working online. I am one of those engineers and have been working remotely for about a year. When I returned to the office after a long time, I realized the ease of casually starting a conversation. I would like to delve deeper into this experience.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Mar 2021 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <category>Remote Working</category>
      <category>Learn</category>
      <category>Scrap</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Micro Frontends on the Client Side (ES Module)</title>
      <link>https://silverbirder.github.io/en-US/blog/contents/client_microfrontends/</link>
      <description>Happy New Year 2021. I look forward to your continued support this year. Recently, I've been working hard on aerobic exercise because I've gained weight. In this article, I would like to talk about Micro Frontends with client-side integration, which I have been testing since last winter. The source code I tested is in the following repository.</description>
      <pubDate>Sat, 16 Jan 2021 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <category>Micro Frontends</category>
      <category>Client Side</category>
      <category>Es Module</category>
      <category>Artifact</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Looking back to 2020</title>
      <link>https://silverbirder.github.io/en-US/blog/contents/2020_furikaeri/</link>
      <description>The year 2020 is now just around the corner. This is the first time I'm blogging about my year in review.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Dec 2020 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <category>Looking Back</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Cloud IDE for Engineers in the COVID-19 Pandemic</title>
      <link>https://silverbirder.github.io/en-US/blog/contents/cloud_ide/</link>
      <description>Since around March 2020, COVID-19 has become prevalent, and it's already December. The way we work has changed significantly, and remote work has become the norm. The way engineers work has also changed. Therefore, I would like to introduce something called a Cloud IDE.</description>
      <pubDate>Sat, 12 Dec 2020 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <category>Cloud IDE</category>
      <category>Engineer</category>
      <category>COVID-19</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Trying ArchUnit with Typescript</title>
      <link>https://silverbirder.github.io/en-US/blog/contents/arch-unit/</link>
      <description>I recently learned about something called ArchUnit. It seems that it can test dependencies. I want to try it out right away, so I'll leave this as a memo.</description>
      <pubDate>Sat, 28 Nov 2020 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <category>Typescript</category>
      <category>Unit Test</category>
      <category>Arch Unit</category>
      <category>Test</category>
      <category>Clean Architecture</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Memo Micro Frontends</title>
      <link>https://silverbirder.github.io/en-US/blog/contents/mfe/</link>
      <description>What are Micro Frontends? Do you know about **Micro Frontends** (hereinafter, MFE)? To put it simply, it is a concept that extends the idea of Microservices to the frontend. We often hear about cases where Microservices are applied on the backend side, but we don't often hear about their application on the frontend.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 19 Nov 2020 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <category>Micro Frontends</category>
      <category>Survey</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Building Micro Frontends with Cloudflare Workers (Edge Worker)</title>
      <link>https://silverbirder.github.io/en-US/blog/contents/cloudflare_workers_mfe/</link>
      <description>This time, I'm going to try building Micro Frontends again. I tried the server-side integration pattern, especially edge-side integration. I will introduce its content. The sample code is left below.</description>
      <pubDate>Sun, 15 Nov 2020 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <category>Cloudflare Workers</category>
      <category>Edge Worker</category>
      <category>Micro Frontends</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>What I, an engineer in my late 20s, need to learn from now on</title>
      <link>https://silverbirder.github.io/en-US/blog/contents/20_study_enginner/</link>
      <description>I am a 26-year-old web engineer. I would like to think a little about how I have learnt about technology in the past and how I will learn about technology in the future.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 29 Oct 2020 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <category>Learn</category>
      <category>Career</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How to Set Up Your Antenna in Technology (Ride on the Shoulders of Giants!)</title>
      <link>https://silverbirder.github.io/en-US/blog/contents/tech_antena/</link>
      <description>Engineers, I believe, usually catch up on technology from various places. It could be through social media, blogs, or videos. So, I would like to introduce how I set up my antenna to catch up on technology.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 Oct 2020 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <category>Antenna</category>
      <category>Technology</category>
      <category>Scrap</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Everything you need to know about Micro Frontends</title>
      <link>https://silverbirder.github.io/en-US/blog/contents/think_micro_frontends/</link>
      <description>I have read more than 100 articles related to Micro Frontends (listed in the reference article). What I learned about Micro Frontends is documented in this post. I also leave my research notes in the following repository.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Oct 2020 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <category>Micro Frontends</category>
      <category>Learn</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Micro Frontends with Zalando tailor (LitElement &amp; etcetera)</title>
      <link>https://silverbirder.github.io/en-US/blog/contents/tailor/</link>
      <description>I tried to build a sample web application with Micro Frontends using Tailor, developed by Zalando. Tailor is an architecture that integrates on the server side. On the client side, I integrated it using Lit Element, which is made with Web Components. I thought I would post what it's all about here.</description>
      <pubDate>Sun, 04 Oct 2020 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <category>Zalando Tailor</category>
      <category>Micro Frontends</category>
      <category>Lit Element</category>
      <category>Artifact</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Micro Frontends with SSR in Ara-Framework</title>
      <link>https://silverbirder.github.io/en-US/blog/contents/ara-framework/</link>
      <description>Hello everyone, my name is silverbirder. My latest interest is Micro Frontends.</description>
      <pubDate>Sun, 23 Aug 2020 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <category>Ara Framework</category>
      <category>Micro Frontends</category>
      <category>SSR</category>
      <category>Artifact</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Apache Beam + Kotlin Development Practical Introduction</title>
      <link>https://silverbirder.github.io/en-US/blog/contents/apache-beam-kotlin/</link>
      <description>Hi there, Re:Zero 2nd season has started 👏, [@silverbirder](https://twitter.com/silverbirder). Recently, I've been using Apache Beam + Kotlin for my work. I didn't know any of those technologies, so I'll write about what I learned in this article ✍️.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 Jul 2020 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <category>Apache Beam</category>
      <category>Kotlin</category>
      <category>Beginner</category>
      <category>Tutorial</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Investigated and Summarized Testing Perspectives for Web Apps (25 Selections)</title>
      <link>https://silverbirder.github.io/en-US/blog/contents/testing_pattern/</link>
      <description>Recently, I learned about the term Property Based Test. I was curious about what other types of tests there are, so I looked into it. This article lists the types of tests. ※ The technology used is chosen in node.js for my convenience.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 Jun 2020 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <category>Web</category>
      <category>Test</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Created a GAS Library, zoom-meeting-creator, to Automatically Generate Zoom Meetings</title>
      <link>https://silverbirder.github.io/en-US/blog/contents/zoom-meeting-creator/</link>
      <description>Are you using Zoom? I have released a GAS library that automatically generates Zoom meetings, and I would like to introduce the background and how to use it.</description>
      <pubDate>Sat, 06 Jun 2020 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <category>Artifact</category>
      <category>Google Apps Script</category>
      <category>Zoom</category>
      <category>Slack</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Introducing a Tool for Bulk Updating Account Images and What I Learned</title>
      <link>https://silverbirder.github.io/en-US/blog/contents/puppeteer_account_manager/</link>
      <description>I developed a tool, puppeteer-account-manager, that can update profile information (images, etc.) for various services like Google and Github all at once. I will introduce the purpose of development and the knowledge gained from it.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Jun 2020 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <category>Artifact</category>
      <category>Learn</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Everything I Learned About Micro Frontends</title>
      <link>https://silverbirder.github.io/en-US/blog/contents/microfrontends/</link>
      <description>There is a web frontend architecture called Micro Frontends. To understand this architecture, I read books and developed a simple sample web application. I would like to record everything I learned from there as minutes.</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 May 2020 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <category>Micro Frontends</category>
      <category>Learn</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Cotlin is a Tool for Collecting Links on Twitter, Discover Presentations from Around the World</title>
      <link>https://silverbirder.github.io/en-US/blog/contents/twitter_cotlin/</link>
      <description>I created a tool called Cotlin to collect links posted on Twitter. The name Cotlin comes from "Collect links in tweet". It's similar to that thing on Android.</description>
      <pubDate>Sun, 15 Mar 2020 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <category>Artifact</category>
      <category>Learn</category>
      <category>Twitter</category>
      <category>Google Apps Script</category>
      <category>Clasp</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Want to be a Virtual Beauty on Mac! (Zoom + Gachikoe + 3Tene or Reality)</title>
      <link>https://silverbirder.github.io/en-US/blog/contents/mac_babiniku/</link>
      <description>The trigger. Are you all doing remote work (telework)? I think the opportunities to use video conferencing tools like Hangouts Meet and Zoom have increased. Amidst this, the following article became popular. Virtual Beauty (Babiniku) is an abbreviation for Virtual Beautiful Girl Incarnation or Virtual Beautiful Girl Self-Incarnation.</description>
      <pubDate>Sun, 08 Mar 2020 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <category>Mac</category>
      <category>Virtual Girl</category>
      <category>Zoom</category>
      <category>Gachikoe</category>
      <category>3Tene</category>
      <category>Reality</category>
      <category>Survey</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Why the Combination of FetchAll and RedirectURL in Google Apps Script is Bad</title>
      <link>https://silverbirder.github.io/en-US/blog/contents/gas_fetchall_redirect/</link>
      <description>I had a problem with Google Apps Script (hereinafter referred to as GAS), so I thought I would leave it as a note.</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Feb 2020 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <category>Google Apps Script</category>
      <category>Learn</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>I tried creating rMinc, a service that registers GMail to GCalendar</title>
      <link>https://silverbirder.github.io/en-US/blog/contents/rminc/</link>
      <description>Target user * People using GMail and GCalendar Isn't it troublesome to open emails? For example, suppose you received the following emails. * An email with the expected delivery date when you purchased a product on Amazon * An email with the screening date when you made an online reservation at a movie theater (TOHO CINEMA) * An email with the stay date when you made an online reservation at a hotel</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Feb 2020 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <category>Artifact</category>
      <category>Learn</category>
      <category>Google Apps Script</category>
      <category>GCalendar</category>
      <category>GMail</category>
      <category>rMinc</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>I Tried Making a One-Frame Comic Search Service Tiqav2 (Algolia + Cloudinary + Google Cloud Vision API)</title>
      <link>https://silverbirder.github.io/en-US/blog/contents/tiqav2_release/</link>
      <description>Conversations with images are fun. Do you use emojis or images when communicating with chat tools? I use them often. When communicating with people, it feels stiff if it's just text. For example, if it's just a phrase like "OK, please proceed with that.", it's hard to understand what kind of emotion the other person has.</description>
      <pubDate>Sat, 08 Feb 2020 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <category>Artifact</category>
      <category>Learn</category>
      <category>Algolia</category>
      <category>Cloudinary</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>I want to test with Google Apps Script too! (Clasp + Typescript + Jest)</title>
      <link>https://silverbirder.github.io/en-US/blog/contents/thing_the_gas_testing_code/</link>
      <description>I have published a library in Google Apps Script (hereafter, GAS). When developing the library, I chose a tech stack of `Clasp + Typescript + Jest` to shorten the test feedback cycle. I would like to share my development experience. I haven't done anything particularly unusual.</description>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Feb 2020 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <category>Google Apps Script</category>
      <category>Test</category>
      <category>Clasp</category>
      <category>Typescript</category>
      <category>Jest</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Things to Keep in Mind When Writing Unit Tests</title>
      <link>https://silverbirder.github.io/en-US/blog/contents/things_to_keep_in_writing_unit_tests/</link>
      <description>I usually write and review unit tests at work. Having unit tests is a good thing, but there is a problem. That is, the rules for unit tests are not clear.</description>
      <pubDate>Sun, 12 Jan 2020 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <category>Unit Test</category>
      <category>Test</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Remote Debugging (Break Point) with IntelliJ + TypeScript + Docker</title>
      <link>https://silverbirder.github.io/en-US/blog/contents/intelliJ_typescript_docker_remote_debug/</link>
      <description>Running `ts-node-dev --inspect=0.0.0.0:9229 ./dist/index.js` on Docker container</description>
      <pubDate>Sat, 28 Dec 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <category>IntelliJ</category>
      <category>Typescript</category>
      <category>Docker</category>
      <category>Remote Debug</category>
      <category>Scrap</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Automatic Unlocking and Considerations with NFC Automation Trigger + SESAME API</title>
      <link>https://silverbirder.github.io/en-US/blog/contents/nfc_automation_trigger_sesame_api/</link>
      <description>Introduction From now on, we will proceed with the discussion assuming iOS, but whether it is iOS or not is not very relevant to the topic of the discussion. With the release of iOS 13.1, NFC Automation Trigger has become available. According to Wiki, NFC is as follows.</description>
      <pubDate>Sat, 28 Dec 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <category>NFC</category>
      <category>SESAME</category>
      <category>IoT</category>
      <category>Life Hack</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Excited about the future of the Web after attending GDG DevFest Tokyo 2019</title>
      <link>https://silverbirder.github.io/en-US/blog/contents/gdg_devfest_tokyo_2019_web/</link>
      <description>I attended an event called GDG DevFest Tokyo 2019. Recently, I haven't been able to find time due to personal circumstances. However, this time, due to work circumstances, I was able to secure some time and attended this event. I even used the Shinkansen from `Osaka to Tokyo` to participate, and there were many discoveries worth it. I thought I would report on what I learned this time.</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Dec 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <category>Report</category>
      <category>GDG</category>
      <category>Dev Fest</category>
      <category>Tokyo</category>
      <category>Web</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Continuously Monitor Visual Regression Tests with CircleCI + BackstopJS (Puppeteer)</title>
      <link>https://silverbirder.github.io/en-US/blog/contents/circle_ci_backstop_visual_regression_testing/</link>
      <description>We have created a tool to continuously monitor visual changes on web pages by combining CircleCI and BackstopJS.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 Nov 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <category>CircleCI</category>
      <category>BackstopJS</category>
      <category>Visual Regression Testing</category>
      <category>Puppeteer</category>
      <category>Test</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Going to the Philippines made me appreciate Japan more</title>
      <link>https://silverbirder.github.io/en-US/blog/contents/Philippines_Travel_Notes/</link>
      <description>From October 11, 2019 to October 15, 2019, I went to the Philippines for five days.</description>
      <pubDate>Sun, 27 Oct 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <category>Philippines</category>
      <category>Japan</category>
      <category>Travel</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Sharing All Experiences of First-time Writing at Techbook Fest 7</title>
      <link>https://silverbirder.github.io/en-US/blog/contents/open_the_techbook7_first_experience/</link>
      <description>I wrote for the first time at Techbook Fest 7. The purpose of this article * A memorandum of what I did in writing * I want to help those who are considering writing The actual book for sale is the one below.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Sep 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <category>Book</category>
      <category>Learn</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Smart Home Conversion for Engineers</title>
      <link>https://silverbirder.github.io/en-US/blog/contents/smart_home_for_enginner/</link>
      <description>Engineers, are you using IoT? By using IoT products essential for smart homes, your life experience will be better. In this article, we will list IoT products for making your home a smart home. If you have a moment of "Is there such a thing?", I'm glad.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Sep 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <category>IoT</category>
      <category>Life Hack</category>
      <category>Smart Home</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Debuting "Introduction to Web Components for Beginners" at Techbook Fest 7!</title>
      <link>https://silverbirder.github.io/en-US/blog/contents/first_release_techbook7/</link>
      <description>I'm publishing a book for the first time! "Introduction to Web Components for Beginners" will be sold at Techbook Fest 7.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 30 Aug 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <category>Web Components</category>
      <category>Book</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Cloud Native Days Tokyo 2019 - Participation Report for July 22-23, 2019</title>
      <link>https://silverbirder.github.io/en-US/blog/contents/cloud_native_days_tokyo_2019/</link>
      <description>This time, I participated in the Cloud Native Days Tokyo 2019 held in Tokyo for two days, so I thought I would report. Rather than reporting on each session, I think I will talk about my overall impressions.</description>
      <pubDate>Sat, 27 Jul 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <category>Report</category>
      <category>Cloud Native Days</category>
      <category>Tokyo</category>
      <category>Kubernetes</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>【Expansion】Frontend de KANPAI! 7 - Going on Reiwa - Participation Report for July 19, 2019</title>
      <link>https://silverbirder.github.io/en-US/blog/contents/frontend_de_kanpai_7/</link>
      <description>This time, I participated in a Frontend event hosted by DeNA, and I would like to report on it. The hashtag is here frokan. Event Overview "Frontend de KANPAI!" (hereinafter, FROKAN) aims to be a community where frontend engineers and those interested in frontend gather, and can exchange ideas and technology in a relaxed manner with a drink in hand.</description>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 Jul 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <category>Report</category>
      <category>Frontend</category>
      <category>Tokyo</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Roundup IT Antenna Sites</title>
      <link>https://silverbirder.github.io/en-US/blog/contents/Roundup_IT_Antenna_Sites/</link>
      <description>Background PyConJP 2019 will be held in September this year. https://pycon.jp/2019/ There was a call for LT, so I started looking for material to apply for LT.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Jul 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <category>IT</category>
      <category>Python</category>
      <category>PyConJP</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>AWS Summit Osaka 2019 Participation Report on June 27, 2019</title>
      <link>https://silverbirder.github.io/en-US/blog/contents/aws_summit_osaka_2019/</link>
      <description>I participated in the "AWS Summit Osaka 2019" held at Grand Front Osaka in Osaka, and I would like to introduce three sessions that I found particularly good.</description>
      <pubDate>Sat, 29 Jun 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <category>AWS</category>
      <category>Report</category>
      <category>Osaka</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>【Increase】Mix Leap Study 45 - Google I/O, WWDC Summary Report! Participation report for June 15, 2019</title>
      <link>https://silverbirder.github.io/en-US/blog/contents/mix_leap_study_45/</link>
      <description>This time, I participated in the following seminar sponsored by Yahoo Corporation. I love both Google and Apple, but I couldn't attend the overseas conference, so this report was full of &lt;b&gt;fresh content&lt;/b&gt; for me. I'm going to write about it in this article.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Jun 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <category>Report</category>
      <category>Mix Leap Study</category>
      <category>Google I/O</category>
      <category>WWDC</category>
      <category>Osaka</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Starting to Learn Kubernetes a Step Behind - 16. Components -</title>
      <link>https://silverbirder.github.io/en-US/blog/contents/start_the_learning_kubernetes_16/</link>
      <description>In the previous "Starting to Learn Kubernetes a Step Behind - 15. Security -", we learned about permissions by RBAC. This time, we will learn about the components of Kubernetes at the end.</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Jun 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <category>Kubernetes</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Starting to Learn Kubernetes a Step Behind - 15. Security -</title>
      <link>https://silverbirder.github.io/en-US/blog/contents/start_the_learning_kubernetes_15/</link>
      <description>In the previous article, Starting to Learn Kubernetes a Step Behind - 14. Scheduling -, we learned about scheduling Pods using Affinity and other methods. This time, we will learn about security.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 07 Jun 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <category>Kubernetes</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Starting to Learn Kubernetes a Step Behind - 14. Scheduling -</title>
      <link>https://silverbirder.github.io/en-US/blog/contents/start_the_learning_kubernetes_14/</link>
      <description>In the previous article, Starting to Learn Kubernetes a Step Behind - 13. Health Checks and Container Lifecycle -, we learned about health checks such as requests and limits. This time, we will learn about scheduling using Affinity and others.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Jun 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <category>Kubernetes</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Osaka, Umeda - Participation Report for Kubernetes Meetup Tokyo 19 Osaka Satellite - May 31, 2019</title>
      <link>https://silverbirder.github.io/en-US/blog/contents/kubernetes_meetup_tokyo_19_osaka_satellite/</link>
      <description>I participated in the Kubernetes Meetup Tokyo from Osaka. I learned about the history of Kubernetes from Joe Beda, one of the three creators of Kubernetes. His talk was very easy to understand and insightful, so I would like to share it.</description>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Jun 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <category>Report</category>
      <category>Kubernetes</category>
      <category>Tokyo</category>
      <category>Osaka</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Starting to Learn Kubernetes a Step Behind - 13. Health Checks and Container Lifecycle -</title>
      <link>https://silverbirder.github.io/en-US/blog/contents/start_the_learning_kubernetes_13/</link>
      <description>In the previous article, Starting to Learn Kubernetes a Step Behind - 12. Resource Limits -, we learned about resource limits such as requests and limits. This time, we will learn about health checks and the container lifecycle.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 30 May 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <category>Kubernetes</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Starting to Learn Kubernetes a Step Behind - 12. Resource Limits -</title>
      <link>https://silverbirder.github.io/en-US/blog/contents/start_the_learning_kubernetes_12/</link>
      <description>In the previous article, Starting to Learn Kubernetes a Step Behind - 11. config&amp;storage Part 2 -, we learned about storage. This time, we will learn about resource limits.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 May 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <category>Kubernetes</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Starting to Learn Kubernetes a Step Behind - 11. config&amp;storage Part 2 -</title>
      <link>https://silverbirder.github.io/en-US/blog/contents/start_the_learning_kubernetes_11/</link>
      <description>In the last time, Starting to Learn Kubernetes a Step Behind - 10. config&amp;storage Part 1 -, we learned about config. This time, we will learn about storage.</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 May 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <category>Kubernetes</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Starting to Learn Kubernetes a Step Behind - 10. config&amp;storage Part 1 -</title>
      <link>https://silverbirder.github.io/en-US/blog/contents/start_the_learning_kubernetes_10/</link>
      <description>In the previous article, Starting to Learn Kubernetes a Step Behind - 09. discovery&amp;LB Part 2 -, we learned about various services. This time, we will learn about the config in config&amp;storage.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 May 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <category>Kubernetes</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Osaka BMXUG Study Meeting -Kubernates Experience &amp; Watson Discovery Introduction- Participation Report on March 27, 2019</title>
      <link>https://silverbirder.github.io/en-US/blog/contents/bmxug_kubernetes_watson_discovery/</link>
      <description>This time, I participated with the aim of experiencing k8s, but there was an unexpected harvest, so I decided to write an article to share it.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 May 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <category>Report</category>
      <category>Osaka</category>
      <category>Kubernetes</category>
      <category>Watson Discovery</category>
      <category>Beginner</category>
      <category>BMXUG</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Osaka GCPUG Kansai ~ Cloud Next Extended ~ - Participation Report on May 14, 2019</title>
      <link>https://silverbirder.github.io/en-US/blog/contents/gcpug_kansai_cloud_next_extended/</link>
      <description>I participated in this event and would like to report on it. The hashtag is here. next19extended Purpose The main event will be explanations and reviews of new Google Cloud services announced at Google Cloud Next '19 San Francisco, held in San Francisco from 04/09 to 04/11 in 2019!</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 May 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <category>Report</category>
      <category>GCP</category>
      <category>Osaka</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Go Conference 2019 Spring - Participation Report on May 18, 2019</title>
      <link>https://silverbirder.github.io/en-US/blog/contents/go_conference_2019_spring/</link>
      <description>I participated in https://gocon.jp and here is my report!</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 May 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <category>Report</category>
      <category>Go Conference</category>
      <category>Tokyo</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Starting to Learn Kubernetes a Step Behind - 09. discovery&amp;LB Part 2 -</title>
      <link>https://silverbirder.github.io/en-US/blog/contents/start_the_learning_kubernetes_09/</link>
      <description>Last time, we learned about the overview of Service in Starting to Learn Kubernetes a Step Behind - 08. discovery&amp;LB Part 1 -. This time, we will learn the following all at once.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 May 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <category>Kubernetes</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Algolia Community Party in Kyoto - 10 May 2019 Participation Report</title>
      <link>https://silverbirder.github.io/en-US/blog/contents/algolia_community_party_in_kyoto/</link>
      <description>I participated here and I will write an article to report back.</description>
      <pubDate>Sat, 11 May 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <category>Report</category>
      <category>Algolia</category>
      <category>Kyoto</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Starting to Learn Kubernetes a Step Behind - 08. discovery&amp;LB Part 1 -</title>
      <link>https://silverbirder.github.io/en-US/blog/contents/start_the_learning_kubernetes_08/</link>
      <description>Last time, we finally finished workloads in Starting to Learn Kubernetes a Step Behind - 07. workloads Part 3 -. This time, I'm thinking of moving on to discovery&amp;LB.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 May 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <category>Kubernetes</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Starting to Learn Kubernetes a Step Behind - 07. Workloads Part 3 -</title>
      <link>https://silverbirder.github.io/en-US/blog/contents/start_the_learning_kubernetes_07/</link>
      <description>In the previous post, Starting to Learn Kubernetes a Step Behind - 06. Workloads Part 2 -, we learned about DaemonSet and StatefulSet (partially). This time, we will continue with StatefulSet and learn about Job, CronJob.</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 May 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <category>Kubernetes</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Starting to Learn Kubernetes a Step Behind - 06. Workloads Part 2 -</title>
      <link>https://silverbirder.github.io/en-US/blog/contents/start_the_learning_kubernetes_06/</link>
      <description>In the previous article, Starting to Learn Kubernetes a Step Behind - 05. Workloads Part 1 -, we learned about Pod, ReplicaSet, and Deployment. This time, we will learn about DaemonSet and StatefulSet (partially).</description>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 May 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <category>Kubernetes</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Starting to Learn Kubernetes a Step Behind - 05. workloads Part 1 -</title>
      <link>https://silverbirder.github.io/en-US/blog/contents/start_the_learning_kubernetes_05/</link>
      <description>In the previous "Starting to Learn Kubernetes a Step Behind - 04. kubectl -", we learned about the kubenetes CLI tool kubectl. This time, we will learn about the main feature, workloads.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 May 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <category>Kubernetes</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Starting to Learn Kubernetes a Step Behind - 04. kubectl -</title>
      <link>https://silverbirder.github.io/en-US/blog/contents/start_the_learning_kubernetes_04/</link>
      <description>In the previous article, Starting to Learn Kubernetes a Step Behind - 03. Raspberry Pi -, we introduced Kubernetes to the RaspberryPi environment. Now that we have successfully confirmed its operation, we would like to start learning right away.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 May 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <category>Kubernetes</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Starting to Learn Kubernetes a Step Behind - 03. Raspberry Pi -</title>
      <link>https://silverbirder.github.io/en-US/blog/contents/start_the_learning_kubernetes_03/</link>
      <description>In the previous article, Starting to Learn Kubernetes a Step Behind - 02. Docker For Mac -, we lightly ran Kubernetes on a Mac. In DockerForMac, the Node was only Master, so it felt insufficient for learning Kubernetes. Therefore, we decided to build a home Kubernetes using RaspberryPi.</description>
      <pubDate>Sun, 28 Apr 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <category>Kubernetes</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Starting to Learn Kubernetes a Step Behind - 02. Docker For Mac -</title>
      <link>https://silverbirder.github.io/en-US/blog/contents/start_the_learning_kubernetes_02/</link>
      <description>In the previous article, Starting to Learn Kubernetes a Step Behind - 01. Environment Selection -, we considered the environment for learning Kubernetes. Instead of using GKE right away, we decided to use DockerForMac, which is easy to try.</description>
      <pubDate>Sat, 27 Apr 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <category>Kubernetes</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Starting to Learn Kubernetes a Step Behind - 01. Choosing the Environment -</title>
      <link>https://silverbirder.github.io/en-US/blog/contents/start_the_learning_kubernetes_01/</link>
      <description>Background I want to be able to use Kubernetes (undefined) But, I have other things I want to do (app development) so I'll put it off for now! So far, I've always put off learning Kubernetes properly, but now I'm going to give it a serious try.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 Apr 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <category>Kubernetes</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Deploying Cloud Run in Just 3 Steps (golang)</title>
      <link>https://silverbirder.github.io/en-US/blog/contents/cloud_run_3_step_glang/</link>
      <description>What is Cloud Run? Cloud Run is a managed compute platform that enables you to run stateless containers that are invocable via HTTP requests. Cloud Run is serverless ※ https://cloud.google.com/run/ More details will be omitted, but it operates serverlessly like Cloud Functions and App Engine. It can also be controlled from GKE because it deploys containers.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Apr 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <category>GCP</category>
      <category>Cloud Run</category>
      <category>Golang</category>
      <category>Deploy</category>
      <category>Scrap</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>SESAME has arrived!</title>
      <link>https://silverbirder.github.io/en-US/blog/contents/Introduce_SESAME/</link>
      <description>Say goodbye to the worry of "Where did I put my key?"</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Apr 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <category>SESAME</category>
      <category>IoT</category>
      <category>Life Hack</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Benefits of Smart Home Appliances</title>
      <link>https://silverbirder.github.io/en-US/blog/contents/Good_Smart_Gadget/</link>
      <description>I will introduce three recommended products that I found useful after actually using them!</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 26 Mar 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <category>IoT</category>
      <category>Life Hack</category>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>